So you've got a video in your app, but you want AI to actually do something
with it,
like generating chapters, moderating your uploads, creating translations, and
more.
Normally, that means you have to stitch together third-party services, building
job queues,
and then also creating custom glue code. With the Mux Robots API, you can skip
all of that.
Robots is a job-based API that runs AI workflows on your Mux assets.
And it's pretty simple. You send an HTTP request to create a
Robots job, and Mux processes that video with that AI workflow.
And you get a structure result back with one API call, or you can use the
dashboard.
So let's look at a few of these workflows, starting with summarization.
When you fire off a summarization job, Mux Robots will give you back a title,
a description, and an array of tags. Some other parameters you can control are
the tone,
so you can change the tone from playful, professional, or neutral.
You can set word limitations for the title and description.
And on top of that, you can also override sections of the prompt as well.
The moderation job samples the frames of your video and moderates each one
frame-by-frame.
You can also set your threshold. The lower the threshold, the stricter the
moderation will be.
And the higher the threshold, the more permissive the model and the moderation
jobs will be as well.
The asked questions job might be the most underrated.
It's actually a lot more powerful than you think, and it's a bit of a Swiss
Army knife.
You can ask a question or a bunch of questions, and you get back a structured
answer.
You also get the confidence score and the reasoning of why that confidence
score was given.
You can use the ask questions job to classify your uploads.
You can route your content and also build decision logic all without training a
model.
The generating chapters job takes analyzation to the next step,
where Mux Robots analyzes your assets caption track to create timestamp
chapters.
When a generating chapters job is completed, you get back an array with the
start time
and also the title of the chapters, which is really good for long-form content.
And if you want to add some customization, you can also change the chapter
density
and the title style by doing a prompt override.
Sifting through a video to find the best moments could take some time.
But with Mux Robots, you also have the Find Key Moments API.
The Find Key Moments job does an audio and visual analyzation
that can help you find the most compelling segments in a video.
Each key moment also comes back with a quality score,
a short title, and a description of what's happening in that key moment.
I can see this job being heavily used for creating highlights from sports games
,
doing social media clips, or previewing content.
The translating captions job is pretty straightforward.
You have your source language, the target language, and your asset ID.
This job will automatically translate an existing caption track
and attach it to your asset with no extra steps.
And lastly, Mux Robots also has jobs to help you manage all of your jobs
across all AI workflows, so you can list, retrieve, or cancel jobs with one API
call.
And that's Mux Robots, a bunch of AI workflows, and one consistent interface.